VANN CALHOUNE

M: 816-612-5559
vanncalhoune@yahoo.com
Vann Calhoune | LinkedIn
https://github.com/Vann-Calhoune

My name is Vann Calhoune. I earned my associates degree from Central Christian College of Kansas with a 3.9 GPA where I was on the basketball team. I have always had an interest in technology and loved to play video games.

About a year ago I started to take an interest in software development. I wanted to build a bot (or an application) that could help me purchase ultra rare shoes. Companies like Nike release limited quantities of select shoes that can resell for 5-10X their original purchase price. I saw an opportunity and wanted to take advantage. I also gained an interest in front end development and started to take online coding courses to become a full stack web developer. After teaching myself how to code for a while I started to really enjoy it. I envisioned a fruitful career in this field. So I wanted to take the next step and learn in a more structured environment, and try to get job ready.

I researched bootcamps and heard a lot of good things about Savvy Coders. This is what drove me to take the Full Stack Web Developer bootcamp. My goal with this bootcamp is to break into the tech field and get my career started.

Technical Skills

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Node, Express, MongoDB, Axios, Navigo, Restful APIs, API testing with Insomnia, Visual Studio Code, Markdown, Git, GitHub, UI/UX, Jira, Agile, SPA's, CRUD Operations, Deploying to Netlify and Heroku.

Continuing Education

Savvy Coders Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp – 2022 Agile Certification through ICAgile – 2022

Savvy graduates receive an Agile Fundamentals Certification. They have demonstrated their understanding of the Agile/Scrum Methodology by presenting a final Capstone Project that embodies the methodology and project preparation. The students work in Jira, create User Stories, manage tasks and contributions to Sprints in Jira. They work in teams to plan Sprints, hold daily standups to groom the backlog, and participate in weekly Sprint Retrospectives. They work on selected user stories and keep communication flowing to ensure everyone is on the same page for the next increment of work. All project tracking is done in Jira.

Capstone Project

I played basketball most my life and I have a love for the game. So for my capstone I decided to create an application catering to basketball enthusiasts like myself. Some of the technologies used to build my project were: HTML, CSS and Javascript for the front end, Node.JS and express.JS for the backend, MongoDB was used as a database, Insomnia was used to test custom APIs, Netlify was used to host the

site online and Heroku was used to make my custom API calls. The website has a blog feature to debate different basketball topics and voice your opinions. There is a feature where you can compare players and their statistics. The last feature is a ranking feature. With this feature you can rank The NBA's 75th anniversary team. You can view the application below.

View App: https://goattakes.netlify.app/

View Code: https://github.com/Vann-Calhoune/Capstone

Experience

Empower Retirement Participant Services November 2021 - Present

- Assist participants with their retirement accounts.
- Duties include assisting with withdrawals, website assistance, going over their plan and general retirement account questions.

Customer Direct

Customer Service

June 2021 - November 2021

- Handled inbound calls, chats and emails from customers.
- Assisted with customer issues, updates, and tech issues.

Trip Mate

Claims Examiner

February 2018 – April 2021

- Processed and determined the outcome of claims.
- Assisted with inbound and outbound calls to customers.
- Critical thinking, customer service, problem solving, time management and de-escalation were critical skills in this role.
- Laid off due to company shut down due to Covid 19.

Education

August 2017 – December 2017 Central Christian College of Kansas Business Administration

August 2016 – May 2017 Central Christian College of Kansas Associate of Arts

August 2014 – May 2015 Lincoln University of MO **Business Administration**